We've seen how to do enumeration to solve the inference problem
我们已经学习了如何在信度网络中利用列举法
on belief networks.
解决推理问题
For a simple network like the alarm network, that's all we need to know.
对于闹钟网络的简单网络而言 这就是我们需要了解的全部内容
There's only five variables.
这里只有 5 个变量
So even if all five of them were hidden,
即使 5 个变量都是隐变量
there'd only be 32 rows in the table to sum up.
表格中只有 32 行需要求和
&gt;From a theoretical point of view we're done, but
从理论角度来讲 我们已经完成了
from a practical point of view, other networks could give us trouble.
但是从实际角度来讲 其他网络会很麻烦
Consider this network, which is one for determining insurance for car owners.
观察这个用于确定车主购买保险的网络
And there are 27 different variables.
这里有 27 个不同的变量
If each of the variables were Boolean,
如果每个变量都是布尔数据类型
that would give us over 100 million rows to sum out.
我们会需要对 1 亿多行求和
But in fact, some of the variables are non-Boolean, they have multiple values.
实际上一些变量不是布尔数据类型 而是多个值
And it turns out that representing this entire network and
实际上为了展现整个网络
doing enumeration, we'd have to sum over a quadrillion rows.
进行列举  我们要对 1000 的五次幂进行求和
That's just not practical.
这并不现实
So, we're going to have to come up with methods that are faster than enumerating
所以我们提出一些方法 远远快于
everything.
列举一切内容
The first technique we can use to get a speed up in doing inference on Bayes
我们在贝叶斯网络中加快推理速度所使用的第一种技巧
nets is to pull out terms from the enumeration.
是从列举中提取项
For example, here, the probability of b is going to be the same for
例如这里 对于 e 和 a 所有值
all values of e and a.
P(+b) 都是相同的
So we can take that term and move it out of the summation, and
所以我们提取这一项 移到求和公式外面
now we have a little bit less work to do.
这样我们的工作量会少一些
We can multiply by that term once rather than having it in each row of the table.
不是让这一项出现在每一行 而是乘以这一项
We can also move this term, the P of e, to the left of the summation over a,
我们也可以移出这一项 P(e) 放在求和公式的左侧
because it doesn't depend on a.
因为它不依赖于 a
By doing this, we're doing less work.
通过这样做我们可以减轻工作量
The inner loop of the summation now has only three terms rather than five terms.
现在求和的内循环只剩下三项 而不是五项
So we reduce the cost of doing each row of the table, but
我们减少了表格每一行的成本
we still have the same number of rows in the table.
但是还包含表格中行数的相同数量
So we're going to have to do better than that.
我们还可以继续优化
The next technique for
接下来有效推理的技巧是
efficient inference is to maximize Independence of variables.
最大化变量的独立性
The structure of a Bayes net determines how efficient it is to
贝叶斯网络的结构决定了它
do inference on it.
进行推理的效率
For example, a network that's a linear string of variables x1 through xn
例如线性字符串变量 X1 到 Xn
can have inference done in time proportional to the number n.
可以根据 n 的比例 O(n) 进行推理
Whereas a network that's a complete network,
虽然这个网络是完整的
where every node points to every other node and so on,
每个节点指向另一个节点
could take time 2 to the n if all n variables are Boolean variables.
如果变量 n 是布尔数据类型 那么得到 2 的 n 次方
Now, in the alarm network we saw previously,
在之前我们见到的闹钟网络中
we took care to make sure that we had all the independence relations
我们务必保证得到了
represented in the structure of the network.
网络结构中展现的所有独立关系
But if we put the nodes together in a different order,
但是如果把这些节点以不同顺序放置
we would end up with a different structure.
我们最后会得到不同的结构
Let's start by ordering the node John calls first, and
我们首先把约翰打电话放在第一个节点
then adding in the node Mary calls.
然后增加节点玛丽打电话
The question is, given just these two nodes, and looking at the node for
那么问题是 在这两个节点的情况下 观察玛丽打电话的节点
Mary calls, is that node dependent or independent of the node for John calls?
与约翰打电话的节点是相互依赖还是相互独立？